Inventory of the Violet L. Barnett Diaries 1931-1972
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Violet L. Barnett Diaries 1913-1972 1931-1972
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2009.504
1.00
35 volumes.
Diaries of Violet Laughead Barnett (d. 1972) of West Chester Pennsylvania for the years 1931-1972 (with the exceptions of 1967 and 1968). Violet Barnett was a homemaker and had two children, Ethel and Earl. Daily entries cover chores, weather, family and social life. There is also the occasional comment on national and international events. Violet Barnett was very engaged in church activities and a member of several chapters of the National Grange.
Barnett, Violet L., d. 1972; Mrs. Batter arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 10/29/2009.
Biographical Note
Married to Joseph Percy Barnett (1882-1967), Violet Laughead Barnett was a homemaker in West Chester, Pa. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Violet L. Barnett.
Scope and Contents
Diaries of Violet Laughead Barnett (d. 1972) of West Chester Pennsylvania for the years 1931-1972 (with the exceptions of 1967 and 1968). Violet Barnett was a homemaker and had two children, Ethel and Earl. Daily entries cover chores, weather, family and social life. There is also the occasional comment on national and international events. Violet Barnett was very engaged in church activities and a member of several chapters of the National Grange.
Also includes are a few newspapers clippings, invitations, greeting cards, postcards, business cards and miscellaneous notes.
Arrangement of Materials
Diaries are arranged in chronological order from 1931-1972. A ledger book from 1920 is contained at the end and the identity of the author is not confirmed.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Grange
Genre/Form of Material:
Clippings (information artifacts); Diaries
Topical Term:
Homemakers--Pennsylvania--Diaries; Pennsylvania--Social life and customs--20th century; Women--Diaries.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Diaries 1931-1932; Marriage Announcement for Violet and Percy Barnett 1913 (1)
  1931 diary contains entries from the end of 1930, beginning with Christmas morning. Marriage announcement is for Violet and Percy Barnett in 1913.
- Diaries 1933-1937 (2)
  First diary contains entries for 1933-35. Diaries for 1936 and 1937 are individual pieces. Notes on the funeral of Percy's father are contained in the entry for February 4th, 1935. Frequent references are also made to the family's lack of money between 1933-1935. Entry for February 24th, 1936 contains a song of tribute to Lincoln from the Grange.
- Diaries 1938-1942 (3)
  First diary contains entries for 1938-40. Diaries for 1941 and 1942 are individual pieces. Contain various newspaper clippings and notes.
- Diaries 1943-1945 (4)
  Contain various newspaper clippings. 1943 contains a birth notice for Ellen Laughead. Photo clip from newspaper of Robert Laughead during World War 2.
- Diaries 1946-1950 (5)
  Entries for 1946 and 1947 are kept together. Entries for 1948 and 1949 are kept together. Diary for 1950 is kept individually. Contain various newspaper clippings, letters and notes. 1947-48 contains a tract from the National Woman's Christian Temperance Union and refrigerator warranty card.
- Diaries 1951-1953 (6)
  Contain various newspaper clippings, advertisements and notes.
- Diaries 1954-1956 (7)
  Contain various newspaper clippings and notes. 1955 contains a birth announcement for Barbara Barnett.
- Diaries 1957-1959 (8)
  1959 Diary contains several postcards.
- Diaries 1960-1962 (9)
  Diaries also contain various newspaper clippings, business cards and postcards. 1960 contains a funeral tag for a car, note reads "Clinton's Funeral." 1962 contains a photograph.
- Diaries 1963-1965 (10)
  Diaries contain various newspaper clippings and church service invitations. 1964 contains a letter to Violet from her grandchild. 1965 contains a postcard from Violet's daughter Ethel.
- Dairies 1966 and 1969; Marraige announcement for Ellen Laughead and Frank Balestrieri 1967 (11)
  Diaries contain various newspaper clippings. Diary from 1966 contains several postcards and memo about the construction of a new Presbyterian Church. 1967 and 1968 were not included in this collection.
- Diaries 1970-72 (12)
  Various newspaper clippings and correspondence with friends are contained in these diaries
  On April 18th, 1972, Violet Barnett was discovered in the den by her son Earl who surmised that his mother had suffered a stroke. Entries from the 18th to the 22nd are then kept by him. Documents Violet's care and the rapid deterioration of her health. She died April 22nd, 1972. A clipping of her obituary is attached inside the diary.
- Ledger Book 1920 (13)
  Contains entries referring to Percy Barnett and the Grange. Possibly authored by Mrs. Batter.